A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial, Series 35 FA374
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Issues and People, 1966-1973; 3; 10 Document Box(es)
  - Biography (Box 11, Folder 143)
    NAR biographical information.
  - Birthday List (Box 11, Folder 144)
    Chronological lists of individuals' birthdays "NAR might like to note."
  - Campaign Thank Yous, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 0144A)
    Copies of letters sent by NAR to individuals who worked on the reelection campaign for President Nixon.
  - Contributors - Nixon, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 0144B)
    "New York Times" clippings on contributions made to the 1972 Nixon Presidential Campaign.
  - Convention, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 145)
    Background information, memoranda, and schedule information for the Republican National Convention, held in Miami Beach.
  - Family Political Contributions (Box 12, Folder 146)
    Sheet summarizing Rockefeller Family contributions to the New York State Republican Committee during 1958-1964.
  - Ford Foundation, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    Article sent by Richard Magat of the Ford Foundation.
  - Free, Lloyd, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    Estimate for polls conducted October 1967.
  - Free Report, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 149)
    Section of polls conducted for NAR on various state and national issues.
  - Governor's Club, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 150)
    List of members in the New York City club. Correspondence from NAR on memberships.
  - Governor's Meeting on Intergovernmental Relations, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 151)
    Transcript of NAR testimony to the Subcommittee on Intergovernmental Relations of the Senate Committee on Government Operations, offered to NAR in advance of meeting with President Johnson or other Governors.
  - Governor's Private Papers, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 0151A)
    Memorandum from David Blabey to Michael Whiteman on the legal implications of NAR's "Governor's Papers."
  - Heiskell, Andrew, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 152)
    Correspondence and memoranda on Heiskell, Chairman of the Urban Coalition.
  - Hinman, George (Box 12, Folder 153)
    Political memoranda sent to NAR by Hinman offering advice on 1968 Presidential Campaign, handwritten correspondence between NAR and Hinman.
  - Housing, New York City, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 154)
    Memorandum from Robert Douglass on low income housing situation in New York City.
  - Hughes, Senator John, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 155)
    Copy of letter sent by State Senator Hughes to State Senator Brydges on solutions for New York State fiscal problems.
  - Human Rights, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 156)
    Press release on New York State's efforts to protect human rights.
  - Human Rights Commission, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 157)
    List of members of the Governor's Committee on Human Rights; Management Survey of the State Commission for Human Rights report.
  - Illinois, Wisconsin, Minnesota Report, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 158)
    1968 report sent to NAR from Governor Shafer on recollections of a trip to the named states by members of Shafer's cabinet.
  - Jerry, Harold, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 159)
    Letter from Mrs. Jerry on the loss of her husband's appointment.
  - Jetport, March 1967 (Box 12, Folder 160)
    Report submitted to NAR on "Jetports and General Aviation in the New York Metropolitian Area."
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 161)
    Transcript of telephone call to President Johnson by NAR on Lyndon B. Johnson's handling of race riots and issues of urban unrest.
  - Jones, Nina, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 162)
    Correspondence and memoranda from Jones; Interim Report, Women's Opportunities Project, November 21, 1966.
  - Jones, Nina, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Latin American Mission, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 164)
    Information file on the trip taken by NAR to Latin American at the request of President Nixon.
  - Latin American Mission - "Letter to the President", 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0164A)
    Report written upon conclusion of Latin American Mission; notation on folder indicates, "Final - sent 8/19/69 to Henry A. Kissinger."
  - Latin American Mission - "Letter to the President", 1969 (Box 13, Folder 0164B)
  - Latin American Mission - Schedule File, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Latin American Mission - Trip File, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Lefkowitz, Stephen, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 167)
    Memorandum to NAR regarding plan by Senator Charles Percy to allow low-income famlies own their own homes.
  - Legislative Opening, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 168)
    Memoranda and list of attendees for buffet held at the Executive Mansion following the opening of the New York State Legislature.
  - Legislative Program, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 169)
    Memoranda concerning actions undertaken in the New York State Legislature during 1967.
  - Lincoln Center Festival (Box 13, Folder 170)
    Report on why the annual summer festival is "an asset to New York."
  - Lindsay, John V., 1967 (Box 13, Folder 171)
    Letter to NAR from Mayor Lindsay regarding South Beach (Staten Island) site conversion for a hospital.
  - Lists, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 0171A)
    Names, addresses of individuals for notes to be sent at conclusion of Nixon reelection campaign.
  - Lists, Addresses, etc., 1972 (Box 14, Folder 172)
    Names, addresses and telephone numbers for gubernatorial staff; Albany State Telephone Dirctories for 1966, 1967.
  - Maine Party, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 173)
    Correspondence concerning the planning of an Open House, sponsored by the Mount Desert Island Republican Committee.
  - March 21, 1968, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 174)
    Copy of Ted Braun document on the events leading up to NAR decision on candidacy; copy of statement.
  - Marshall, Alton G., 1967 (Box 14, Folder 175)
    Weekly reports on developments, July-November 1967.
  - Medicaid, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 176)
    Correspondence and memoranda regarding Medicaid proposals.
  - Meeting at 812, March 10, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 177)
    Minutes and notes from strategy meeting; clippings regarding meeting; correspondence from NAR expressing thanks for attending.
  - Meeting Notes, 1970-1971, no date (Box 14, Folder 178)
    Lists of attendees for meetings; agendas, notes and memoranda.
  - Meeting Reports, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 179)
    Reports offered by T. N. Hurd on meetings held with NAR.
  - Message to the Legislature, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 180)
    Printed brochure of NAR's Annual Address, delivered Janaury 3, 1968.
  - Minority Groups in News Media, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 181)
    Press release announcing the appointment of additional members to the Committee on Minority Groups.
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 182)
    Meeting minutes from a meeting held May 17, 1968 (date not confirmed).
  - Morrow, Hugh, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 183)
    Memorandum from Morrow concerning possible book projects.
  - Narcotics Program, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 184)
    Memorandum from Al Marshall on the work of the Narcotics Addiction Control Commission.
  - NAR Notes (Box 15, Folder 185)
    Folders of Rockefeller's handwritten notes from meetings; reminder slips.
  - NAR Notes (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - NAR Notes (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - National Governors Conference, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 188)
    Correspondence and memoranda on the 59th Annual Meeting of the National Governors' Conference, held in Chicago, Illinois.
  - National Guard, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 189)
    Memoranda concerning proposed reorganization of the New York National Guard.
  - Negro Heritage Library, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 190)
    Correspondence and memoranda with information on complaints made to the library.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 191)
    Primarily political clippings on the 1968 presidential race.
  - New York City Parks Commission, no date (Box 15, Folder 192)
    List of members.
  - New York Delegation (Washington, D.C.), 1968 (Box 15, Folder 193)
    List of members and committee assignments for the state delegation to Congress.
  - New York State Business, 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 194)
    Reports, statements and press releases on actions taken on issues concerning New York State.
  - New York State Teachers Association, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 195)
    Text of citation given to NAR, November 20, 1967.
  - New York Young Republicans, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 196)
    Correspondence, primarily with William Nickerson, president of the New York Young Republican Club.
  - Nixon, Richard, 1966, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 197)
    Nixon's letter on future of party and U.S. foreign policy, November 8, 1966; Nixon's telegram of congratulations for 1966 win; exchange of correspondence on proposals for public assistance (welfare).
  - Oregon, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 198)
    Political information, memoranda, and polls on NAR support in the state.
  - Pierce, Larry, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 199)
    Monthly report of the Narcotic Addiction Control Commission.
  - Party, June 9, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 200)
    List of attendees for Dinner Dance.
  - Pennsylvania Society Speech, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 201)
    Hugh Morrow draft of speech.
  - Pennsylvania Society Statistics, no date (Box 16, Folder 202)
    Mary McAniff memo on education, welfare, and medicaid spending in New York State.
  - Platform, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 203)
    Correspondence and memoranda on plans and proposal for the 1968 Republican Party Platform.
  - Policy Committee Meeting (GOP Governors Association), 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 204)
    Background information and memoranda on the Republican Governor's Task Force, assigned the responsibility of assisting in the writing of the 1968 platform.
  - Politics, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 205)
    Correspondence on the use of National Media Analysis to take polls on political issues.
  - Pollution, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 206)
    Press release on NAR program to control air and water pollution.
  - Power Committee (empty folder) (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - Power Proposal, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 208)
    List of members of "Governor's Electric Power Committee;" New York State proposals on electric power.
  - Portugal, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 209)
    Correspondence with Portuguese citizens, exchange of pleasantries.
  - Potential Program Items, 1966 Campaign (Box 16, Folder 0209A)
    Background material submitted to NAR from William Ronan on 59 issues that could be discussed in the 1966 gubernatorial campaign.
  - "Quiet Hour" (1967) (Box 16, Folder 210)
    Planning memoranda for meeting to discuss Senator Javits' plan to get high-level candidates for Congress.
  - "Quiet Hour" (1968) (Box 16, Folder 211)
    Minutes of "Quiet Hour" meeting to discuss the New York Citiy sanitation crisis.
  - Rats, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 212)
    Report on the New York State Rodent Control Porgram.
  - "Read", 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 213)
    Three articles/reports for NAR to see and comment on" "We Can Cope with the Coming Suburban Explosion," "Fortune," September 1966; Position Paper of Louis Lefkowitz on the "Proposition that the Present Constitutional Provision for the Election of the Attorney General Should Be Retained"; article, "State Legislatures and the Crisis in the Cities."
  - "Reference", 1967 (Box 16, Folder 214)
    Reports and memoranda on various issues.
  - Reorganization of the London (United Kingdom) Government, 1965-1971 (Box 16, Folder 215)
    Memoranda and correspondence; associated report, "National Health Service Reorganization."
  - Reports, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 216)
    Assorted reports on national and state issues.
  - Reports - "A Presentation to the President's Council for Urban Affairs on the Fiscal Crisis in the Federal System, Dramatized by Problems in Urban Areas, New York State", 1969 (Box 17, Folder 0216A)
    Report send to NAR from Political Surveys and Analyses.
  - Reports - "The Implications of Communist Nuclear Weapons Technology", 1972; Three numbered copies of report. (Box 17, Folder 0216B)
    Report by Kenneth C. Bandtel, Cahrles I. Teevan, Edward Teller.
  - Reports - "The Implications of Communist Nuclear Weapons Technology", 1972; Three numbered copies of report. (Box 17, Folder 0216C)
  - Reports - "The Implications of Communist Nuclear Weapons Technology", 1972; Three numbered copies of report. (Box 17, Folder 216)
  - Reports - "International Attitudes in Four Asian Democracies", 1969 (Box 17, Folder 0216E)
    Report by Lloyd Free.
  - Republican Convention, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 217)
    Correspondence with Jim Hellmuth on housing arrangements for the 1968 Republican Convention.
  - Republican Coordinating Committee, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 218)
    Position papers for the 1968 Republican Platform.
  - Republican Governors Association, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 219)
    Summary of proceedings from 1968 regular meeting; list of members of GOP Governors Policy Committee; unfinished business from 1967.
  - Republican Governors Conference, 1966-1968 (Box 18, Folder 220)
    Information on the organization; summary of proceedings of 1967 meeting.
    Two albums of photos, one titled "1973 Spring Republican Governors Conference, New York, New York," the other "1973 National Governors Conference, Lake Tahoe, Nevada" were removed from this series and placed with the Nelson A. Rockefeller Photograph Collection.
  - Republican National Convention/Committee, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 221)
    Republican Platform, 1968; Press Releases from the Convention, including Pennsylvania Governor Shafer's speech nominating Nelson Rockefeller.
  - Republican Party in State, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 222)
    Clippings, correspondence and memoranda on party politics in New York State.
  - Republican State Committee, no date (Box 18, Folder 223)
    List of names of New York State County Chairmen.
  - Robinson, Jackie, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 224)
    Memorandum from Robinson to NAR on 1968 election; appointment of Ray Schaffer to Robinson's office.
  - Romney, George, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 225)
    Clippings concerning Governor Romney's declaration as a candidate for President in 1968.
  - Ronan, William J., 1967 (Box 18, Folder 226)
    Mail leaflet asking position on bond issue.
  - Sanitation Crisis (1968-New York City) (Box 18, Folder 227)
    Information, press release, and memoranda on the strike by sanitationmen in New York City.
  - Sanitationmen's Strike, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 228)
    Transcript of TV interview with NAR on strike.
  - Schriever, General B. A., 1967 (Box 18, Folder 229)
    Correspondence with retired Air Force General on his work in urban problems.
  - Sheffield, Joseph, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 230)
    Report on how to strengthen the appeal of the Republican Party to younger voters.
  - Simpson, Frank E., 1967 (Box 18, Folder 231)
    Correspondence with the former chair of the State Employees Division of the Tri-State Area.
  - Signatures, no date (Box 18, Folder 232)
    Blank Executive Chamber stationery with "Nelson" signed at bottom.
  - Speeches, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 233)
    Press release of NAR remarks.
  - Speech, April 18, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 234)
    Speech delivered to the American Society of Newspaper Editors on "The Making of a Just America."
  - Speech, May 1, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 235)
    Speech delivered to the World Affairs Council of Philadelphia on "The Building of a Just World Order."
  - Speech, June 24, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 236)
    Speech delivered to the National Newspaper Association on the economy.
  - States Urban Action Center, no date (Box 19, Folder 237)
    Report, "Action for Our Cities, A Preliminary Report."
  - Stewart, Richard, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 238)
    Reports on the work undertaken by the State Insurance Department.
  - Standard Oil of New Jersey, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 239)
    Report from the Employee Relations Department of Standard Oil of New Jersey on the strike by New York City Sanitationmen.
  - Stone, Robert D., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 240)
    Status reports on appointments made by NAR.
  - Strategy, no date (Box 19, Folder 241)
    Un-attributed memo on suggested positions for NAR as a presidential candidate.
  - Thayer Letter, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 242)
    Letter from Walter N. Thayer on New York State financial issues.
  - Tobin, Austin, Jr. (Republican Finances), 1966 (Box 19, Folder 243)
    Report on the Finance Committee of the New York Republican State Committee.
  - Transportation, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 244)
    Memoranda on the status of Long Island Rail Road trians on time efficiency; press release on NAR proposal for a federal Department of Transportation; transportation bond issue reports.
  - Transportation Bond Issue, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 245)
    Correspondence with members of New York State legislature, newspaper publishers, and citizens following approval of bond issue.
  - Urban Development Corporation, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 246)
    Press releases and statement regarding creation of the Urban Development Corporation.
  - Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 247)
    Clippings, memoranda, reports on status of United States involvement in Vietnam; Free Preliminary Report on American Opinion About Vietnam (1968); NAR Statements on Vietnam (December 1967, July 1968).
  - Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 248)
  - Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 249)
  - Vietnam - State Post Vietnam Planning Committee, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 250)
    Press release on the committee's plans to help veterans returning from the war in Vietnam.
  - Walker, Wyatt Tee, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 251)
    Memo from Walker on issues covered at a Symposium on New York State issues.
  - Water Pollution, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 252)
    Transcript of NAR address to Conference on Water Pollution of Hudson River.
  - Welfare, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 253)
    List of attendees to the "Governors Conference on Public Welfare;" associated reports.
  - Wells, Jack, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 254)
    Reports from Wells on New York City political issues.
- Campaign 1968, 4; 3 Document Box(es)
  This subseries contains material pertaining to Governor Rockefeller's run for the Republican Presidential nomination in 1968. The subseries is comprised primarily of lists of individuals who assisted on the campaign and were to receive thank you notes from Governor Rockefeller. At the conclusion of the subseries is an alphabetical run of state files. These files contain press releases announcing the naming of state chairs of Rockefeller for President committees in 39 states and the District of Columbia. File titles containing the name of a city and a date, indicate a "trip briefing book" outlining scheduled appearances by Governor Rockefeller in that state. File folders for the remaining 11 states were empty and were discarded during processing.
  - Advertising - T. Losee, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 255)
    List of employees at Jack Tinker and Partners, who worked on the "Rockefeller Account."
  - Arts and Entertainment, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 256)
    Index cards of individuals in the entertainment industry who were sent thank you notes by NAR.
  - Citizens, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 257)
    List of individuals who worked for various "Citizens for Rockefeller" groups.
  - Committees for Rockefeller, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 258)
    Names of state committee leaders; list of DNA employees.
  - Delegates, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 259)
    List of delegates to convention; indications to those who pledged support to NAR.
  - Delegates (Deardourff - Intelligence), 1968 (Box 21, Folder 260)
    List of delegate names and addresses to send thank you notes to.
  - DAR Research, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 261)
    Names and addresses of DNA and Washington office individuals for thank you letters.
  - Endorsements, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    Names and addresses of well-known academicians, lawyers, doctors, clergy, and athletes who endorsed NAR.
  - Endorsements, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 263)
    Governors and Congressmen who endorsed NAR.
  - Endorsements, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 264)
    Prominent people who endorsed NAR.
  - Ethnic Groups - Scelsi, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 265)
    List of names and addresses from Michael Scelsi for NAR thank you notes.
  - Finance, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 266)
    Draft thank you letters and lists of individuals on the National Finance Committee.
  - Finance Committee of the Rockefeller for President Committee, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 267)
    Report prepared by John Hay Whitney and Walter N. Thayer for use in closing days of campaign and at convention, contains lists of names of members of committees.
  - Labor, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 268)
    Lists of labor individuals to be sent thank you notes.
  - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 269)
    Assorted lists of individuals to be sent thank you notes.
  - Names, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 270)
    Alphabetical list of names of delegates to the Republican Convention.
  - Negro Task Force, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 271)
    List of prominent African Americans who contributed to the campaign.
  - "New Majority", 1968 (Box 22, Folder 272)
    Assorted lists of individuals who assisted with the "New Majority" state campaigns.
  - Rockefeller for President Steering Committee House of Representatives (empty folder), 1968 (Box 22, Folder 273)
  - Scandanavian Americans for Rockefeller, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 274)
    Draft letter and list of names for thank you letter.
  - Staff, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 275)
    List of staff members who worked on campaign.
  - State Committee Chairmen, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 276)
    Cumulative lists of all Republican State Chairmen, Vice Chairmen and Republican National Committeemen and Committeewomen.
  - Volunteers, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 277)
    List of individuals who volunteered on the Rockefeller for President Campaign.
  - Washington Office - Abrahams, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 278)
    List of names for employees in the Washington DC office of Rockefeller for President.
  - Westchester Citizens for Rockefeller, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 279)
    List of names and addresses of Westchester residents who worked on campaign.
  - Women's Group - Adkins, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 280)
    List of members of women's groups for Rockefeller to be sent thank you notes from NAR.
  - Alabama, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 281)
  - Arkansas, June 28, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 282)
    LIttle Rock
  - California, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 283)
  - Colorado, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 284)
  - Connecticut, June 26, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 285)
    New Haven, Meriden, Hartford
  - Delaware, June 22, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 286)
    Wilmington
  - Georgia, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 287)
  - Hawaii, July 5, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 288)
    Honolulu
  - Idaho, July 2, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 289)
    Boise
  - Illinois, June 20, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 290)
    Chicago
  - Iowa, June 27, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 291)
    Sioux City
  - Kansas, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 292)
  - Kentucky, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 293)
  - Maine, June 24, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 294)
    Portland
  - Maryland, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 295)
  - Massachusetts, June 24, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 296)
    Boston
  - Michigan, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 297)
  - Minnesota, May 8, 1968; June 15, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 298)
    Duluth
  - Missouri, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 299)
  - Montana, July 2, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 300)
    Helena
  - Nebraska, June 28, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 301)
    Lincoln
  - Nevada, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 302)
  - New Jersey, June 18, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 303)
    Newark, New Brunswick
  - New Mexico, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 304)
  - New York, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 305)
  - North Dakota, June 15, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 306)
    Fargo
  - Ohio, June 19, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 307)
    Cleveland
  - Oklahoma, June 28, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 308)
    Oklahoma City
  - Oregon, July 3, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 309)
    Eugene, Albany, Portland
  - Pennsylvania, June 17, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 310)
    Philadelphia
  - South Dakota, June 27, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 311)
    Sioux Falls, Huron
  - Texas, June 29, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 312)
    San Antonio
  - Utah, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 313)